LUQMAN HAQIM

No. 4, Lorong Alma Jaya 30, Taman Alma Jaya, 14000 Bukit Mertajam, Penang.



ABOUT ME

Name: Luqman Haqim Bin Mat Idrus Date of Birth: 17th August 1994

Nationality: Malaysian

CGPA: 3.11

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS 🔉



Microsoft Office	000000000
HTML & CSS	00000000
Visual Basic	00000000
C / C++	00000000
Python	00000000
JavaScript	0000000
Assembly	0000000

LANGUAGES **(0)**

MATLAB



0000000

REFERENCES &

Dr Nan Bin Mad Sahar

Academic Advisor Senior Lecturer, FKEE, UTHM

Tel: +6012 9422 771 Email: nan@uthm.edu.my

Dr Maisara Binti Othman

Final Year Project Supervisor Deputy Dean HEPA, FKEE, UTHM

Tel: +6010 7604 317

Email: maisara@uthm.edu.my

OBJECTIVES



I am Lugman Hagim. I am an innovative problem solver. Highly adaptable to new ideas. Able to learn new procedures quickly. I can process and apply new skills efficiently. I would like to be a part of a company where I could use and enhance my skills as well as gain experience for the future development of myself.

WORKING EXPERIENCES



INTERN - (JUN 2016 - SEP 2016)

Majlis Perbandaran Seberang Perai, Penang

- Assigned to the Engineering Department.
- Electrical unit, assisted in equipment maintenance work, building wiring, machinery servicing, and lighting installation.
- Street lamp unit, analyzed street light damaged throughout Seberang Perai.
- R&D unit, took part in innovation of street light pole improvement for the state.
- Underwent the traffic light system course at Advance Dynamic System Sdn Bhd.

PART TIME - (JUN 2013 - AUG 2013)

TESCO Bukit Mertajam

- Cashier with 3 months hands-on experience in handling goods and interacting with people.
- Assisted customers to have great shopping experiences.
- Demonstrated attention to detail and ability to work in a self-directed manner.
- Worked effectively as a team member accurately scanning products and maintaining displays.

EDUCATION



BACHELOR DEGREE IN ELECTRONIC

ENGINEERING (Hons.)

(2013 - 2017)

University Tun Hussein Onn Malaysia

Majoring in Computer.

CGPA: 3.11

FOUNDATION IN BIOLOGICAL SCIENCES

(2012 - 2013)

Universiti Malaya

CGPA: 2.52

SIJIL PELAJARAN **MALAYSIA**

(2010 - 2011)

Maktab Rendah Sains MARA Pengkalan

Chepa 8A & 2A+

Rekacipta elective subject.

COURSES TAKEN

☑ Academic English

☑ Advanced Microcontroller

☑ Analog Electronics

☑ Artificial Intelligence

☑ Computer Architecture And Organisation

☑ Computer Network

☑ Computer Programming

☑ Computer Systems Engineering

☑ Creativity And Innovation

☑ Data Structures And Algorithms

☑ Digital Design

☑ Digital Electronics

☑ Digital Signal Processing

☑ Effective Communication

☑ Electric Circuits

☑ Electrical Technology

☑ Electromagnetic Fields And Waves

☑ Electronics Circuit Analysis And Design

☑ Electronics Communication Systems

☑ Electronics Engineering Laboratory I To IV

☑ Engineering Economics

☑ Engineering Management

☑ Engineering Mathematic I To V

☑ Engineering Practices

☑ Engineers And Society

☑Entrepreneurship

☑ Ethnic Relations

☑ Final Year Project 1 & 2

☑ Image Processing

☑ Instrumentation And Control Systems

☑Integrated Design Project I & II

☑ Islamic And Asian Civilization

☑ Islamic Studies

☑ Mandarin Language

☑ Microprocessor And Microcontroller

☑ Multimedia Technology And Application

☑ Nationhood & Current Development Of Malaysia

☑ Networks And Adv. Microcontroller Laboratory

☑ Object Oriented Programming

☑Occupational Safety And Health

☑ Operating System

☑ Power Systems

☑ Signals And Systems

☑ Technical Writing

☑VLSI System Design

☑PALAPES I & II

EXTRA CURRICULAR

• ONE STEP TO SUCCESS

- o Participant
- University level

PEWARIS MUDA NEGARA 1MALAYSIA

- o Participant
- Intervarsity level

• FKEE STUDENTS MOBILITY TO TAIWAN 2016

- o Treasury & Fundraising Head Committee
- International level

• MISI BANTUAN BANJIR 2017

- Participant
- National level

• FKEE STUDENTS MOBILITY TO JAPAN 2017

- o Publicity & Media Bureau
- International level

PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN 🚱



- ▶ Diode & Transistors Application
- Machine Learning Optimization Algorithm
- ★ Simultaneous Multithreading Issues
- **▶** C++ Software Development Methods Application
- **▶** Parallel Computing Using OpenMP
- ★ 8bit ALU Simple Computer & Calculator
- ▶ Digital Banner Circuit Design
- Filters & Algorithm Design Using MATLAB
- ▶ Phase Shift Oscillator Circuit

- ▶ PID Analysis Using MATLAB Simulink

THESIS EXCERPT

The aim of the project is to create a transceiver system for devices to communicate with each other using VLC on Arduino boards. It works by switching the current to the LEDs off and on at a very high rate. An LED is used to send binary data in the form of light streams that is received by another LED which demodulates the light signal. Frame encapsulation and Manchester encoding are used where the data are packed in a frame between a start and stop symbol while the LED light intensity are varied. Transmitter and receiver are combined into a transceiver. Two devices can communicate with each other sending 32bytes of data per second in low ambient light condition within 1.2m distance.